Siddharth Verma

♦ https://siddharthverma314.github.io | ≤ siddharthverma314@gmail.com

About me

I am an ML Researcher with deep expertise in training state-of-the-art LLMs. I write performant low-level code to train models across thousands of GPUs. I also conduct research in both academic and industrial settings, resulting in publications in prestigious venues like NeurIPS and ACL.

Languages: Python, Haskell, Rust, Java, SQL, C, Go, CUDA, RISC-V

Skills: Language Modeling, LLM Pretraining, Reinforcement Learning, Neural Networks, Statistics **Technologies:** Pytorch, JAX, OpenAl Triton, Pallas, Docker, NixOS, Unix/Bash, Git, Google Cloud

Experience

GDM Research Engineer

■ Google Deepmind **♥** Cambridge MA

□ Aug 2024-Current

- Core contributor to Gemini Pretraining in both model architecture and implementation
- Wrote a performant pallas kernel for 2-simplical attention to enable research into higher order attention
- · Investigated numerical instability in MoE implementation and its effects on pretraining and RL

Research Engineer

■ Character.ai **•** New York NY

Dec 2023-Aug 2024

- Contributed to all aspects of LLM pretraining from fundamental research to performant implementations
- Discovered the relation between attention and intelligence in LLMs and its corresponding scaling laws
- Designed scaling laws to predict a 10,000x flops extrapolation in validation loss with tight error bounds
- Implemented multiple MoE variants for our flagship model trained across our entire cluster of GPUs
- Investigated the non-causality of Expert Choice MoEs and when this affects model performance

Senior Machine Learning Engineer

■ Square • Boston MA

□ Sep 2022-Dec 2023

- Finetuned open-source LLMs on merchant-buyer conversations to suggest replies to incoming messages
- Conducted an online A/B test and demonstrated a 5% increase in suggestion acceptance rate
- Designed and implemented a multi-task training system to incorporate classification tasks into an LLM
- Instruction finetuned FLAN-T5 on internal data and evaluated performance against individual classifiers

AI Resident

■ Meta (Facebook) Seattle WA

□ Aug 2021-Sep 2022

- Wrote code to process 1TB of multimodal data using Rust and Parquet for a 20x speedup against Python
- Automated the training LLMs of up to 13B parameters on large multi-node clusters with up to 64GPUs
- Evaluated whether training on explanations improve reasoning capabilities of LLMs, and found that explanations mostly benefit mathematical reasoning
- Analyzed effect of masking rates and masking strategies in multimodal learning, showing that increasing masking rate nullifies effects of different masking strategies

Undergraduate Researcher at Robotic AI and Learning Lab

■ Berkeley Artificial Intelligence Research Lab • Berkeley CA

□ Jan 2019-May 2021

- Worked with Prof. Sergey Levine and Prof. Chelsea Finn on RL and NLP in domains of robotics and chatbots
- Designed and implemented a multi-agent RL algorithm to learn composable locomotive skills without manual environment resets, subsequently using them to solve a maze. Published at NeurIPS
- Used Offline RL to finetune LLMs to bargain on craigslist items, beating supervised learning in human evals across all metrics. Accepted as oral presentation at NAACL

Education

BA Computer Science & Music

♥ UC Berkeley ◆ GPA: 3.965, Major GPA: 4.0